## **Deanna Madon**

Plano, TX

Phone: 817-915-5348 | Email: deanna.madon@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://tinyurl.com/dmadonlinkedin | Portfolio: https://tinyurl.com/dmadonportfolio

GitHub: https://github.com/dmadon

#### SUMMARY

Entry-level Full-Stack Web Developer seeking to gain job experience. Professional certificate earned from SMU Continuing and Professional Education. Experience with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js and MySQL. Familiar with using GitHub for version control and project collaboration. Over 15 years of experience in Office Management and Administration specializing in optimizing productivity, efficiency and service quality. Highly dependable, ethical and reliable support specialist that blends advanced organizational, technical and business acumen. Works effectively with cross-functional teams in ensuring operational and service excellence.

#### **SKILLS**

**Software/Platforms/Frameworks:** MongoDB, Express, React, Node, MySQL, Bootstrap, Handlebars, GitHub, Heroku, Microsoft Word, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Access, Microsoft PowerPoint

Software Languages: JavaScript

**Other Skills:** Professional written and oral communication, organization, problem solving, collaboration, time management, punctuality

## **PROJECTS**

#### Too Good to Waste

https://github.com/dmadon/too-good-to-waste | https://too-good-2-waste.herokuapp.com/

- This application seeks to help address the problem of food waste in America by allowing grocery stores to pre-package boxes of close-to-expiration foods and sell them at a reduced price.
- Contributed all back-end processes and integrated the Stripe payment platform.
- MongoDB, Express, React, Node (MERN Stack), Mongoose, GraphQL, Apollo Server, Chakra UI, React Google Maps API, bcrypt, JavaScript.

## **Absence Reporting Tool**

https://github.com/dmadon/absence-reporting | https://absence-reporting.herokuapp.com/

- A practical business tool that allows a user to request time off from work. The employee's supervisor is notified by email of the absence requests and, when logged in, can easily approve or deny the absence from an approval queue.
- Contributed all front-end and back-end code to this project.
- mySQL, Sequelize, Express, Node, Handlebars, Nodemailer, bcrypt, JavaScript.

#### **Note Taker**

https://github.com/dmadon/note-taker | https://note-taker-module11.herokuapp.com/

- A simple tool for writing and saving notes and reminders. Users can create new notes and add them to a list of saved notes. Notes may also be edited or deleted.
- Contributed all back-end code to this project. Front-end code was provided.
- Node, Express, JavaScript

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Office Manager, Elementary Academic Services Department

March 2017 - Current

District Plano, TX

Plano Independent School District

- Allocate and manage an approximately \$600,000.00 budget for Elementary Academic Services department.
- Maximize budget savings to the district by comparing and negotiating vendor prices.
- Place orders for goods and services and manage the release of payment upon completion of orders.
- Facilitate the timely reconciliation of staff corporate credit card statements and travel reimbursements.
- Mentor new support staff on district processes and procedures to achieve maximum production.
- Ensure compliance with district retention schedule by maintaining electronic and physical filing systems.
- Manage office operations while scheduling appointments for department managers.
- Verify and reconcile absence reports for all department staff monthly.
- Assign travel and leadership stipends to department staff for each fiscal year.

### **Key Accomplishments:**

- o Built a budget tracking system for the Federal Grants Department which facilitated the tracking of estimated and actual expenses by project, budget line, and spending category using Microsoft Access.
- Nominated for the Superintendent's Service Award, February 2020. This is an award for district support staff who consistently exceed expectations.

## Secretary, Elementary Academic Services Department

February 2007 - March 2017

Plano Independent School District

Plano, TX

- Recorded and tracked operational expenses to identify and eliminate wasteful spending.
- Booked airfare, hotel, and ground transportation to coordinate office travel.
- Maintained office supplies inventory by checking stock and ordering new supplies.
- Created and updated records and files to maintain document compliance.
- Responded to emails and other correspondence to facilitate communication and enhance business processes.

#### **Key Accomplishments:**

- Built a reporting system used district-wide for providing progress reports to parents of kindergarten through second-grade students using Microsoft Access.
- o Nominated for the Superintendent's Service Award, February 2014.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Professional Certificate, Full Stack Web Development** Southern Methodist University, Dallas, TX

May 2022 - November 2022

**Bachelor of Arts: Music Performance** Texas Woman's University, Denton, TX August 1998 – May 2002